<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<library>
    <author>
        <name>Aristotle</name>
        <full_name>Aristotle</full_name>
        <quote>
            <text>It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought without accepting it.</text>
            <text>Happiness is the meaning and the purpose of life, the whole aim and end of human existence.</text>
            <text>No great mind has ever existed without a touch of madness.</text>
            <text>I count him braver who overcomes his desires than him who conquers his enemies, for the hardest victory is over self.</text>
            <text>Excellence is never an accident. It is always the result of high intention, sincere effort, and intelligent execution; it represents the wise choice of many alternatives – choice, not chance, determines your destiny.</text>
            <text>The high-minded man must care more for the truth than for what people think.</text>
            <text>Those who know, do. Those that understand, teach.</text>
            <text>Wishing to be friends is quick work, but friendship is a slow ripening fruit.</text>
            <text>Learning is not child’s play; we cannot learn without pain.</text>
            <text>Dignity does not consist in possessing honors, but in the consciousness that we deserve them.</text>
            <text>Anybody can become angry — that is easy, but to be angry with the right person and to the right degree and at the right time and for the right purpose, and in the right way — that is not within everybody’s power and is not easy.</text>
            <text>Time crumbles things; everything grows old under the power of time and is forgotten through the lapse of time.</text>
            <text>Misfortune shows those who are not really friends.</text>
            <text>Whatever lies within our power to do lies also within our power not to do.</text>
            <text>For the things we have to learn before we can do them, we learn by doing them.</text>
            <text>A friend to all is a friend to none.</text>
            <text>He who has overcome his fears will truly be free.</text>
            <text>He who cannot be a good follower cannot be a good leader.</text>
            <text>Fear is pain arising from the anticipation of evil.</text>
            <text>It is of the nature of desire not to be satisfied, and most men live only for the gratification of it.</text>
        </quote>
    </author>

    <author>
        <name>Cicero</name>
        <full_name>Marcus Tullius Cicero</full_name>
        <quote>
            <text>It is exercise alone that supports the spirits, and keeps the mind in vigor.“</text>
            <text>Any man can make mistakes, but only an idiot persists in his error.“</text>
            <text>A home without books is a body without soul.“</text>
            <text>The eyes like sentinel occupy the highest place in the body.“</text>
            <text>Dogs wait for us faithfully.“</text>
            <text>What nobler employment, or more valuable to the state, than that of the man who instructs the rising generation.“</text>
            <text>It is exercise alone that supports the spirits, and keeps the mind in vigor.“</text>
            <text>A room without books is like a body without a soul.“</text>
            <text>The safety of the people shall be the highest law.“</text>
            <text>We think a happy life consists in tranquility of mind.“</text>
            <text>The pursuit, even of the best things, ought to be calm and tranquil.“</text>
            <text>The higher we are placed, the more humbly we should walk.“</text>
            <text>A sensual and intemperate youth translates into an old worn-out body.“</text>
            <text>A tear dries quickly when it is shed for troubles of others.“</text>
            <text>In a disordered mind, as in a disordered body, soundness of health is impossible.“</text>
            <text>Let the punishment match the offense.“</text>
            <text>Just as the soul fills the body, so God fills the world. Just as the soul bears the body, so God endures the world. Just as the soul sees but is not seen, so God sees but is not seen. Just as the soul feeds the body, so God gives food to the world.“</text>
            <text>The safety of the people shall be the highest law.“</text>
            <text>In times of war, the law falls silent.“</text>
            <text>No one has the right to be sorry for himself for a misfortune that strikes everyone.“</text>
            <text>For of all gainful professions, nothing is better, nothing more pleasing, nothing more delightful, nothing better becomes a well-bred man than agriculture.“</text>
            <text>Old age: the crown of life, our play's last act.“</text>
            <text>The harvest of old age is the recollection and abundance of blessing previously secured.“</text>
            <text>Our country is wherever we are well off.“</text>
            <text>It is exercise alone that supports the spirits, and keeps the mind in vigor.“</text>
            <text>Man's best support is a very dear friend.“</text>
            <text>What nobler employment, or more valuable to the state, than that of the man who instructs the rising generation.“</text>
            <text>It is foolish to tear one's hair in grief, as though sorrow would be made less by baldness.“</text>
            <text>Let us drink for the replenishment of our strength, not for our sorrow.“</text>
            <text>The authority of those who teach is often an obstacle to those who want to learn.“</text>
        </quote>
    </author>

    <author>
        <name>Seneca</name>
        <full_name>Lucius Annaeus Seneca</full_name>
        <quote>
            <text>True happiness is to enjoy the present, without anxious dependence upon the future, not to amuse ourselves with either hopes or fears but to rest satisfied with what we have, which is sufficient, for he that is so, wants nothing. </text>
            <text>Luck is what happens when preparation meets opportunity.</text>
            <text>All cruelty springs from weakness.</text>
            <text>Begin at once to live, and count each separate day as a separate life.</text>
            <text>Throw me to the wolves and I will return leading the pack.</text>
            <text>As is a tale, so is life: not how long it is, but how good it is, is what matters.</text>
            <text>They lose the day in expectation of the night, and the night in fear of the dawn.</text>
            <text>Every night before going to sleep, we must ask ourselves: what weakness did I overcome today? What virtue did I acquire?</text>
            <text>Difficulties strengthen the mind, as labor does the body.</text>
            <text>We are always complaining that our days are few, and acting as though there would be no end of them.</text>
            <text>It is not because things are difficult that we do not dare; it is because we do not dare that things are difficult.</text>
            <text>Associate with people who are likely to improve you.</text>
            <text>Man is affected not by events but by the view he takes of them.</text>
            <text>We suffer more often in imagination than in reality.</text>
            <text>You want to live but do you know how to live? You are scared of dying and tell me, is the kind of life you lead really any different from being dead?</text>
            <text>Time heals what reason cannot.</text>
            <text>The greatest blessings of mankind are within us and within our reach. A wise man is content with his lot, whatever it may be, without wishing for what he has not.</text>
            <text>Hang on to your youthful enthusiasms — you’ll be able to use them better when you’re older.</text>
            <text>You act like mortals in all that you fear, and like immortals in all that you desire.</text>
            <text>If a man knows not to which port he sails, no wind is favorable.</text>
            <text>It is not the man who has too little, but the man who craves more, that is poor. </text>
            <text>It is the power of the mind to be unconquerable.</text>
            <text>The bravest sight in the world is to see a great man struggling against adversity.</text>
            <text>It is not that we have so little time but that we lose so much. … The life we receive is not short but we make it so; we are not ill provided but use what we have wastefully.</text>
            <text>If you really want to escape the things that harass you, what you’re needing is not to be in a different place but to be a different person.</text>
            <text>He suffers more than necessary, who suffers before it is necessary.</text>
            <text>Wealth is the slave of the wise. The master of the fool.</text>
            <text>Until we have begun to go without them, we fail to realize how unnecessary many things are. We’ve been using them not because we needed them but because we had them.</text>
            <text>Sometimes even to live is an act of courage.</text>
            <text>Life is never incomplete if it is an honorable one. At whatever point you leave life, if you leave it in the right way, it is whole.</text>
        </quote>
    </author>

    <author>
        <name>Socrates</name>
        <full_name>Socrates</full_name>
        <quote>
            <text>The only true wisdom is in knowing you know nothing.</text>
            <text>Beware the barrenness of a busy life.</text>
            <text>By all means, marry. If you get a good wife, you’ll become happy; if you get a bad one, you’ll become a philosopher.</text>
            <text>I decided that it was not wisdom that enabled poets to write their poetry, but a kind of instinct or inspiration, such as you find in seers and prophets who deliver all their sublime messages without knowing in the least what they mean.</text>
            <text>Be as you wish to seem.</text>
            <text>To know, is to know that you know nothing. That is the meaning of true knowledge.</text>
            <text>I know that I am intelligent, because I know that I know nothing.</text>
            <text>A system of morality which is based on relative emotional values is a mere illusion, a thoroughly vulgar conception which has nothing sound in it and nothing true.</text>
            <text>He is richest who is content with the least, for content is the wealth of nature.</text>
            <text>True wisdom comes to each of us when we realize how little we understand about life, ourselves, and the world around us.</text>
            <text>The unexamined life is not worth living.</text>
            <text>There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance.</text>
            <text>I cannot teach anybody anything. I can only make them think.</text>
            <text>Wonder is the beginning of wisdom.</text>
            <text>Be kind, for everyone you meet is fighting a hard battle.</text>
            <text>To find yourself, think for yourself.</text>
            <text>Strong minds discuss ideas, average minds discuss events, weak minds discuss people.</text>
            <text>Education is the kindling of a flame, not the filling of a vessel.</text>
            <text>Be slow to fall into friendship, but when you are in, continue firm and constant.</text>
            <text>He who is not contented with what he has, would not be contented with what he would like to have.</text>
            <text>Death may be the greatest of all human blessings.</text>
            <text>Envy is the ulcer of the soul.</text>
            <text>Get not your friends by bare compliments, but by giving them sensible tokens of your love.</text>
            <text>If a man is proud of his wealth, he should not be praised until it is known how he employs it.</text>
            <text>Regard your good name as the richest jewel you can possibly be possessed of – for credit is like fire; when once you have kindled it you may easily preserve it, but if you once extinguish it, you will find it an arduous task to rekindle it again. The way to gain a good reputation is to endeavor to be what you desire to appear.</text>
            <text>Remember that there is nothing stable in human affairs; therefore avoid undue elation in prosperity, or undue depression in adversity.</text>
            <text>Remember what is unbecoming to do is also unbecoming to speak of.</text>
            <text>The shortest and surest way to live with honour in the world, is to be in reality what we would appear to be; and if we observe, we shall find, that all human virtues increase and strengthen themselves by the practice of them.</text>
            <text>Think not those faithful who praise all thy words and actions; but those who kindly reprove thy faults.</text>
            <text>Thou shouldst eat to live; not live to eat.</text>
            <text>Bad men live that they may eat and drink, whereas good men eat and drink that they may live.</text>
            <text>Not life, but good life, is to be chiefly valued.</text>
            <text>If all misfortunes were laid in one common heap whence everyone must take an equal portion, most people would be contented to take their own and depart.</text>
            <text>Once made equal to man, woman becomes his superior.</text>
            <text>Only the extremely ignorant or the extremely intelligent can resist change.</text>
            <text>The greatest way to live with honor in this world is to be what we pretend to be.</text>
            <text>The way to gain a good reputation is to endeavor to be what you desire to appear.</text>
            <text>People demand freedom of speech to make up for the freedom of thought which they avoid.</text>
            <text>Wisdom begins in wonder.</text>
            <text>When the debate is over, slander becomes the tool of the loser.</text>
            <text>The hour of departure has arrived and we go our ways; I to die, and you to live. Which is better? Only God knows.</text>
            <text>The hottest love has the coldest end.</text>
            <text>Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak.</text>
            <text>Our prayers should be for blessings in general, for God knows best what is good for us.</text>
            <text>Employ your time in improving yourself by other men’s writings so that you shall come easily by what others have labored hard for.</text>
            <text>From the deepest desires often come the deadliest hate.</text>
            <text>The envious person grows lean with the fatness of their neighbor.</text>
            <text>Contentment is natural wealth, luxury is artificial poverty.</text>
            <text>Call no man unhappy until he is married.</text>
            <text>Let him that would move the world, first move himself.</text>
            <text>The only good is knowledge and the only evil is ignorance.</text>
            <text>We cannot live better than in seeking to become better.</text>
            <text>The nearest way to glory is to strive to be what you wish to be thought to be.</text>
            <text>The easiest and noblest way is not to be crushing others, but to be improving yourselves.</text>
            <text>False words are not only evil in themselves, but they infect the soul with evil.</text>
            <text>The mind is everything; what you think you become</text>
            <text>Remember, no human condition is ever permanent. Then you will not be overjoyed in good fortune nor too scornful in misfortune.</text>
            <text>It is better to change an opinion than to persist in a wrong one.</text>
            <text>Mankind is made of two kinds of people: wise people who know they’re fools, and fools who think they are wise.</text>
            <text>Get not your friends by bare compliments, but by giving them sensible tokens of your love.</text>
            <text>By all means marry. If you get a good spouse you’ll become happy, while if you get a bad one you’ll become a philosopher.</text>
        </quote>
    </author>
</library>